<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travel on mjec&#39;s electric blogaloo</title>
    <link>https://mjec.blog/tags/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travel on mjec&#39;s electric blogaloo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mjec.blog/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on New York City</title>
      <link>https://mjec.blog/2016/06/28/reflections-on-new-york-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjec.blog/2016/06/28/reflections-on-new-york-city/</guid>
      <description>This is one of the nicest cities I&amp;rsquo;ve ever been to. And by that I mean the people in New York City are lovely.
This came as kind of a shock to me. Everyone talks about how New Yorkers are rude, or how this is a dangerous place. I have never felt that. I have been scared precisely once: walking through &amp;ldquo;downtown Brooklyn&amp;rdquo; at 3am, past a construction site on a dimly lit alley I rounded a hard corner and a plastic bag jumped out at me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day one</title>
      <link>https://mjec.blog/2016/03/22/day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjec.blog/2016/03/22/day-one/</guid>
      <description>According to my watch pedometer, I walked 23,160 steps in the last six hours.
I started at about eight this morning by walking to the nearest train station. Realising that it was rush hour and I hadn&amp;rsquo;t had breakfast, I doubled back to have breakfast before trying to negotiate the subway. I had a two egg and cheese; the guy behind the counter asked me what sort of bread and I said &amp;ldquo;bagel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I have arrived</title>
      <link>https://mjec.blog/2016/03/21/i-have-arrived/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjec.blog/2016/03/21/i-have-arrived/</guid>
      <description>Door to door was about 30 hours, but I&amp;rsquo;m now in New York City. It&amp;rsquo;s 7:30pm and I&amp;rsquo;m about to go to bed.
I watched a lot of TV on the plane. Of it all, my favourite line came from an episode of Bored To Death: &amp;ldquo;He was Jewish and really smart. A member of menscha!&amp;rdquo; What I didn&amp;rsquo;t do much of on the plane was sleep.
The first thing that struck me about New York is that it&amp;rsquo;s big.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travelling is hard</title>
      <link>https://mjec.blog/2016/03/20/travelling-is-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjec.blog/2016/03/20/travelling-is-hard/</guid>
      <description>I have a place to live. I have tickets. I have a purpose, starting 28 March. Now I just need to get there.
I always forget how much effort is involved in travelling. I have the rest of the day to pack my things and then I leave the house around 4am tomorrow. I&amp;rsquo;ll arrive at my temporary accommodation about thirty hours later (assuming no delays).
Packing itself is hard. There is a lot just in deciding what to take (and what to take carry-on).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>